You Wu

University of Southern California, Los Angeles, CA 90089, USA Phone: (213)713-5454 Email: youwu@usc.edu

JOB INTERESTS

Have solid background in both Software and Hardware. Have project experience in Operating System(OS), compiler(LLVM), security mitigations in computer architecture level. Open to any SDE positions and CPU/GPU architecture designs. Strong coding ability in Python, C/C++, as well as debugging experiences in Unix/Linux with simulators such as Gem5.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, C/C++, Verilog, Java, SQL, HTML, Markdown

Tools: Git, Unix/Linux, GDB, Gem5, TensorFlow, AWS, QEMU, GCC, LLVM

EDUCATION

Ph. D. in Computer Engineering at University of Southern California

Ming Hsieh Department of Electrical Engineering

M. S. in Computer Science at University of Southern California

Department of Computer Science

Aug. 2017 – Dec. 2020

Supervisor: Xuehai Qian

Aug. 2017 - present

GPA:3.63/4.0

B. E. in Microelectronic Science and Engineering at Tsinghua University, China Aug. 2013 - Jul. 2017

Department of Microelectronics and Nanoelectronics

Thesis: The VLSI implementation of Binarized Neural Networks

Overall GPA: 89.2/100 Rank: 5/26

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Intern | Alibaba Group U.S.

Advisor: Dr, Lide Duan, Alibaba DAMO Academy

May. 2022 – Aug. 2022

- Worked on a project of Control Flow Integrity on RISC-V ISA
- **Qemu** profiling on proposed branch landing scheme defending for Jump Oriented Programming (JOP) attacks
- Proposed two extensions on branch landing scheme: one for Return Oriented Programing (ROP) defense, the other for function level fine-grained protection
- Designed a workflow to evaluate the proposed extension
- modified the LLVM source code to transmit IR to the target machine code with added defense instructions

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

RL for Side Channel Attacks | University of Southern California | Research Assistant

Jan. 2023 – present

- Advisor: Prof. Xuehai Qian, University of Southern California
- Investigated on the current Deep Reinforcement learning frameworks on Interconnects
- Reproduced the interconnects side channel attacks on AWS servers
- Built the training framework to accomplish the side channel attacks

Defense for the Frontend Attack | University of Southern California | Research Assistant. Oct. 2021 – May. 2022 Advisor: Prof. Xuehai Qian, University of Southern California

- Frontend paths including LSD, DSB and MITE have the vulnerability to side channels
- Trying to enhance the **gem5** simulator to simulate the Frontend behaviors
- Proposed to use partition techniques with delaying update in the Frontend to eliminate speculative effects

Rowhammer Attack Project | University of Southern California | Research Assistant.

Apr. 2021 – Dec. 2021

- Advisor: Prof. Xuehai Qian, University of Southern California
- Focus on counter-based mitigation protecting the DRAM from rowhammer attack
- Investigated the state-of-the-art rowhammer mitigation strategies
- Reproducing the existing work using different rowhammer simulators

The Reversible Coherence Protocol | University of Southern California | Research Assistant. Sep. 2018 – Nov. 2021 Advisor: Prof. Xuehai Qian, University of Southern California

- Analyzed resent defense strategy like InvisiSpec and CleanupSpec.
- Designed a buffer-based Undo approach to mitigate the transient speculation flaw.
- Extended the current memory coherence protocol to support the merging and purging requests in our design
- Added processor support which help securely issue speculative instructions instead of blocking them
- Proposed a comprehensive mitigation which could eliminate the current speculation related attacks and interferences

GPU Power Virus Project | University of Southern California | Research Assistant.

Apr. 2018 - Nov. 2018

Advisor: Prof. Xuehai Qian, University of Southern California

- Used genetic algorithm to automatically generate extremely high power consumption.
- Modified **gpgpusim** simulator to trace the access pattern for gpgpu simulations.

Design of a Specialization BNN Accelerator | Tsinghua University | Research Assistant Sep. 2016 - Jul. 2017 Advisor: Prof. Shouyi Yin, Institute of Microelectronics

- Designed an architecture which can efficiently execute the binarized neural computation.
- Investigated its application in different neural networks to accelerate computation.

Implementation of BNN on different platforms | Cornell University | Research Assistant. Jun. 2016 - Sep. 2016 Advisor: Prof. Zhiru Zhang, Dept. of Electrical and Computer Engineering

- Implemented both the hardcore and softcore of the BNN network on an **FPGA** hardware.
- Coded for the interface to connect the Rocket chip softcore with the BNN accelerator.
- Used High Level Synthesis tool **Stratus** to utilize limited resources to implement the project.

Vehicular behavior algorithm analysis | Tsinghua University | Research Assistant.

Sep. 2015 - Jun. 2016

Advisor: Prof. Shouyi Yin, Institute of Microelectronics

- Used deep learning algorithms to analyze human behavior while driving a vehicle.
- Used the deep learning platform "tensorflow" to solve traditional problems, e.g. MNIST classification.
- Investigated the mechanism behind deep learning algorithms.

Pilot Assignment Algorithms for Wireless Networks | Tsinghua University | SRT Project. Mar. 2015 – May. 2016 Advisor: Prof. Wei Feng, Dept. of Electronic Engineering

- Investigated pilot assignment algorithms to achieve better performance in cellular MIMO systems.
- Performed simulation in cellular Gaussian networks to verify the theoretical results.

AWARDS

Recipient of the Annenberg Fellowship supported by the Viterbi School of Engineering 2017 Recipient of School Scholarship for Outstanding Academic Award, 2014 Two-time recipient of School Scholarship for Literary Award of Excellence, 2014, 2016

PUBLICATIONS

[arXiv] A Case for Reversible Coherence Protocol

You Wu, Xuehai Qian preprint arXiv: 2006.16535

[CCF Trans HPC] ReBNN: in-situ acceleration of binarized neural networks in ReRAM using complementary resistive cell

Linghao Song, You Wu, Xuehai Qian, Hai Li, Yiran Chen

CCF Transactions on High Performance Computing 1, no. 3-4 (2019): 196-208.

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Fall 2022 Teaching Assistant: EE557 Computer Systems Architecture
Fall 2021 Teaching Assistant: EE557 Computer Systems Architecture
Summer 2020 Teaching Assistant: EE559 Mathematical Pattern Recognition

Summer 2018 Student Volunteer at ISCA'18